

Roman Biriukov

Product | Delivery | Launch -HealthTech, BI, AI, TrafficTech

- @ romapr1me@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/pr1me

Skills

Product Management

Drives product vision and full lifecycle management

B2B, B2C, SaaS, Web, Desktop, Mobile

Project Management

Plans and coordinates multiple teams and resources

Backlog, Roadmap, Scrum, OKRs

Agile Methodologies

Manages backlogs and iterative releases

Sprints, Daily stand-ups, Review

Team Management

Collaborates across departments, resolves blockers, and keeps teams motivated

Leadership, Cross-functional sync, Conflict resolution

MVP & Experimentation

Validates hypotheses and gathers early feedback

A/B, EAP, ProductHunt

Analytics & Decision-Making

Uses data to prioritize features and optimize product outcomes

Data-driven, Reporting, Dashboards

Independence & Accountability

Highly self-driven, transparent, and oriented toward results

Ownership, Proactive, Self-motivation

Presentations & Documentation

Creates engaging demos, tutorials, and technical content

Demo, Screencast, Tutorial, User guides

Languages

Russian

Native

English C1

15 years in digital & product development, launching 25+ solutions (B2B, B2C, SaaS, on-prem, native) in BI, HealthTech, TrafficTech, Reporting, and E-commerce. Focused now on Gen AI and NLP technologies. Guided the journey from 0 to 1, taking products from concept to launch. I handle discovery and delivery—acting as both product and project manager—coordinating multiple teams, stakeholders, and departments.

Experience

RETABLE 01.2023 - 12.2024

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER

USA

https://www.tabula.io

Launched Tabula from stealth to public release, including Product Hunt launch; Achieved 25x MAU growth; Introduced Tomat and rolled out an EAP for both products; Implemented Stripe for subscriptions and lifetime licensing; Achieved 20x MRR increase; Embedded GenAl using OpenAl API; Cut lead time by 50%.

ALUNA HEALTH

01.2017 - 12.2022

HEAD OF PRODUCT

USA

https://www.alunahealth.com

Initiated pilot projects in multiple hospital networks; Launched Aluna Health app, increasing MAU from 0 to 10k+; Automated clinical data extraction with mCODE standard; Deployed Radiology Dashboard with PACS integration, and summary notes; Released a cloud solution for precision medicine for oncologists and patients; Developed a patient recruitment system for clinical trials.

BIARUM 01.2012 - 12.2022

PRODUCT & PROJECT MANAGER

Russia

https://www.biarum.com

Managed development for Harward Library of Evidence; Supported and developed ANCR; Launched FHIR Sandbox for InterSystems IRIS for Health; Launched reporting portal for First Line Software; Implemented remote scheduling for radiology centers; Launched portal for MIT Living Labs campus.

01.2017 - 01.2019 TICON

SENIOR PROJECT MANAGER https://www.ticon.co

USA

Automated traffic analysis reports, reducing several days of manual work; Launched dashboard for managing map sources and traffic detector data.

01.2015 - 12.2016 **PDFFILLER**

PROJECT MANAGER

USA

https://www.pdffiller.com

Rewrote PDF editor from Flash to JavaScript, enhancing performance, stability, and browser/mobile support.

IMPROVE LABS 01.2012 - 12.2015

PRODUCT & PROJECT MANAGER

https://familyhistory.invitae.com

USA

Launched PowerLineage, a cloud service for genetic counselor and geneticists (iPad + Web), acquired by Invitae and rebranded as Family History Tool; Developed

medical questionnaire builder; Integrated genetic test results.

GO2SEE 01.2010 - 12.2012

PRODUCT & PROJECT MANAGER

Russia

https://mego.travel

Designed portal (main page and checkout funnel); Launched product and started processing customer orders.

Education

SPbGIK 2008

Informatics and Analytics

References

Anastasia

RETABLE co-founder

Roman is an exceptional CPO with a background in software dev, AI, big data, and NLP projects.

As a truly professional product manager, Roman has the ability to wear multiple hats—acting as a programmer, database analyst, UX engineer, designer, software tester, and end-user advocate.